Baby Shannon -- you can see her on the left -- is doing much better now, and Ryan got a job by taking some of our courses. So what made these courses so different? After all, online course content has been available for a while. What made it different was that this was real course experience. It started on a given day, and then the students would watch videos on a weekly basis and do homework assignments. And these would be real homework assignments for a real grade, with a real deadline. You can see the deadlines and the usage graph. These are the spikes showing that procrastination is global phenomenon. (Laughter) At the end of the course, the students got a certificate. They could present that certificate to a prospective employer and get a better job, and we know many students who did. Some students took their certificate and presented this to an educational institution at which they were enrolled for actual college credit. So these students were really getting something meaningful for their investment of time and effort. Let's talk a little bit about some of the components that go into these courses. The first component is that when you move away from the constraints of a physical classroom and design content explicitly for an online format, you can break away from, for example, the monolithic one-hour lecture. You can break up the material, for example, into these short, modular units of eight to 12 minutes, each of which represents a coherent concept. Students can traverse this material in different ways, depending on their background, their skills or their interests. So, for example, some students might benefit from a little bit of preparatory material that other students might already have. Other students might be interested in a particular enrichment topic that they want to pursue individually. So this format allows us to break away from the one-size-fits-all model of education, and allows students to follow a much more personalized curriculum. Of course, we all know as educators that students don't learn by sitting and passively watching videos. Perhaps one of the biggest components of this effort is that we need to have students who practice with the material in order to really understand it. There's been a range of studies that demonstrate the importance of this. This one that appeared in Science last year, for example, demonstrates that even simple retrieval practice, where students are just supposed to repeat what they already learned gives considerably improved results on various achievement tests down the line than many other educational interventions. We've tried to build in retrieval practice into the platform, as well as other forms of practice in many ways. For example, even our videos are not just videos. Every few minutes, the video pauses and the students get asked a question. (Video) SP: ... These four things. Prospect theory, hyperbolic discounting, status quo bias, base rate bias. They're all well documented. So they're all well documented deviations from rational behavior. DK: So here the video pauses, and the student types in the answer into the box and submits. Obviously they weren't paying attention. (Laughter) So they get to try again, and this time they got it right. There's an optional explanation if they want. And now the video moves on to the next part of the lecture. This is a kind of simple question that I as an instructor might ask in class, but when I ask that kind of a question in class, 80 percent of the students are still scribbling the last thing I said, 15 percent are zoned out on Facebook, and then there's the smarty pants in the front row who blurts out the answer before anyone else has had a chance to think about it, and I as the instructor am terribly gratified that somebody actually knew the answer. And so the lecture moves on before, really, most of the students have even noticed that a question had been asked. Here, every single student has to engage with the material. And of course these simple retrieval questions are not the end of the story. One needs to build in much more meaningful practice questions, and one also needs to provide the students with feedback on those questions. Now, how do you grade the work of 100,000 students if you do not have 10,000 TAs? The answer is, you need to use technology to do it for you. Now, fortunately, technology has come a long way, and we can now grade a range of interesting types of homework. In addition to multiple choice and the kinds of short answer questions that you saw in the video, we can also grade math, mathematical expressions as well as mathematical derivations. We can grade models, whether it's financial models in a business class or physical models in a science or engineering class and we can grade some pretty sophisticated programming assignments. Let me show you one that's actually pretty simple but fairly visual. This is from Stanford's Computer Science 101 class, and the students are supposed to color-correct that blurry red image. They're typing their program into the browser, and you can see they didn't get it quite right, Lady Liberty is still seasick. And so, the student tries again, and now they got it right, and they're told that, and they can move on to the next assignment. This ability to interact actively with the material and be told when you're right or wrong is really essential to student learning. Now, of course we cannot yet grade the range of work that one needs for all courses. Specifically, what's lacking is the kind of critical thinking work that is so essential in such disciplines as the humanities, the social sciences, business and others. So we tried to convince, for example, some of our humanities faculty that multiple choice was not such a bad strategy. That didn't go over really well. So we had to come up with a different solution. And the solution we ended up using is peer grading. It turns out that previous studies show, like this one by Saddler and Good, that peer grading is a surprisingly effective strategy for providing reproducible grades. It was tried only in small classes, but there it showed, for example, that these student-assigned grades on the y-axis are actually very well correlated with the teacher-assigned grade on the x-axis. What's even more surprising is that self-grades, where the students grade their own work critically -- so long as you incentivize them properly so they can't give themselves a perfect score -- are actually even better correlated with the teacher grades. And so this is an effective strategy that can be used for grading at scale, and is also a useful learning strategy for the students, because they actually learn from the experience. So we now have the largest peer-grading pipeline ever devised, where tens of thousands of students are grading each other's work, and quite successfully, I have to say. But this is not just about students sitting alone in their living room working through problems. Around each one of our courses, a community of students had formed, a global community of people around a shared intellectual endeavor. What you see here is a self-generated map from students in our Princeton Sociology 101 course, where they have put themselves on a world map, and you can really see the global reach of this kind of effort. Students collaborated in these courses in a variety of different ways. First of all, there was a question and answer forum, where students would pose questions, and other students would answer those questions. And the really amazing thing is, because there were so many students, it means that even if a student posed a question at 3 o'clock in the morning, somewhere around the world, there would be somebody who was awake and working on the same problem. And so, in many of our courses, the median response time for a question on the question and answer forum was 22 minutes. Which is not a level of service I have ever offered to my Stanford students. (Laughter) And you can see from the student testimonials that students actually find that because of this large online community, they got to interact with each other in many ways that were deeper than they did in the context of the physical classroom. Students also self-assembled, without any kind of intervention from us, into small study groups. Some of these were physical study groups along geographical constraints and met on a weekly basis to work through problem sets. This is the San Francisco study group, but there were ones all over the world. Others were virtual study groups, sometimes along language lines or along cultural lines, and on the bottom left there, you see our multicultural universal study group where people explicitly wanted to connect with people from other cultures. There are some tremendous opportunities to be had from this kind of framework. The first is that it has the potential of giving us a completely unprecedented look into understanding human learning. Because the data that we can collect here is unique. You can collect every click, every homework submission, every forum post from tens of thousands of students. So you can turn the study of human learning from the hypothesis-driven mode to the data-driven mode, a transformation that, for example, has revolutionized biology. You can use these data to understand fundamental questions like, what are good learning strategies that are effective versus ones that are not?
La pequeña Shannon, a la izquierda, está mucho mejor, y Ryan consiguió un empleo por formarse en algunos de nuestros cursos. ¿Qué hizo estos cursos tan diferentes? Si bien los cursos en línea han estado disponibles durante un tiempo la diferencia estuvo en que estos recreaban la experiencia de una clase real. Empezaban en un día determinado, los estudiantes veían los videos sobre una base semanal y se les asignaban tareas. Tareas reales con valor para una calificación real y una fecha de entrega definida. Aquí ven las fechas límite y el gráfico de uso del sitio. Estos picos demuestran que el posponer es un fenómeno global. (Risas) Al final del curso los estudiantes recibieron un certificado. Lo podían presentar a un posible empleador para obtener un mejor empleo, y conocemos a muchos que lo hicieron. Algunos lo presentaron en su institución educativa para validar créditos. Así que los estudiantes obtuvieron algo valioso a cambio de su tiempo y esfuerzo. Ahora hablemos sobre algunos componentes de estos cursos. El primero es que cuando se dejan atrás las restricciones físicas del aula y se diseñan contenidos explícitamente para una clase virtual, se puede escapar, por ejemplo, del inflexible formato de una hora. Puedes fraccionar el material, por ejemplo, en unidades cortas de entre 8 y 12 minutos, que constituyen cada una un concepto coherente. Los estudiantes pueden revisar el material de diferentes formas, dependiendo de sus conocimientos previos, habilidades e intereses. Por ejemplo, algunos se benefician del material preparatorio que otros ya conocen. Otros pueden estar interesados en un tema particular que quieren seguir de forma individual. Este formato nos permite abandonar el modelo educativo en que todo es igual para todos y permite a los estudiantes seguir un currículo más personalizado. Por supuesto, como educadores sabemos que no se aprende viendo videos de forma pasiva. Quizá uno de los mayores componentes del proyecto es que necesitamos tener estudiantes que practiquen con el material para asegurar su comprensión. Numerosos estudios han demostrado la importancia de esto. Este, que apareció en Science el año pasado, por ejemplo, demuestra que incluso el simple repaso de retención, que consiste en solo repetir lo aprendido, produce una mejora considerable en los resultados de varias pruebas de rendimiento, superando otro tipo de intervenciones didácticas. Tratamos de incorporar el repaso de retención, entre otras formas de práctica. Por ejemplo, nuestros videos son más que videos. Cada pocos minutos hay una pausa y se plantea una pregunta. (Video) SP: …Teoría de la perspectiva, descuento hiperbólico, sesgo del statu quo y sesgo de conocimiento previo, son desviaciones cognoscitivas bien documentadas del pensamiento racional. DK: Aquí viene una pausa, el estudiante escribe su respuesta en el recuadro y la envía. Obviamente no puso atención. (Risas) Así que intenta de nuevo y esta vez acierta. Si lo desea, puede revisar la explicación. Ahora el video continúa. Esa fue una pregunta fácil de las que yo podría hacer en clase, pero cuando las hago, el 80 % de los alumnos aún está anotando lo último que dije, el 15 % está distraído en Facebook, y el sabelotodo de enfrente grita la respuesta antes de que el resto pueda reflexionarla. Y yo estoy muy complacida de que alguien haya sabido la respuesta. La clase continúa y la mayoría ni siquiera nota que hice una pregunta. Aquí, cada estudiante debe interactuar con el contenido. Desde luego, hay mucho más que estas simples preguntas. Se deben incorporar ejercicios más significativos y retroalimentar a los estudiantes en todos ellos. ¿Cómo calificar el trabajo de 100 000 estudiantes si no se tienen 10 000 asistentes? La respuesta es dejar a la tecnología hacerlo por ti. Y por fortuna, la tecnología ahora nos permite evaluar una diversidad interesante de tareas. Además de las preguntas de opción múltiple y de respuesta corta como la que mostré, podemos evaluar expresiones y derivaciones matemáticas. Podemos calificar modelos, bien sean financieros en una clase de negocios, o físicos en una clase de ciencias o ingeniería, y también ejercicios sofisticados de programación. Les mostraré uno sencillo, pero muy visual. Es de la clase Ciencias de la Computación 101, de Stanford. Los estudiantes deben corregir el color de esta imagen roja borrosa. Escriben su programa dentro del explorador, pero no muy bien, la Estatua de la Libertad aún parece enferma. Así que intentan de nuevo y lo logran, y ahora pueden ir al siguiente ejercicio. Esta posibilidad de interactuar activamente con el material y recibir evaluación inmediata es esencial para el aprendizaje. Aunque aún no podemos evaluar por completo las actividades que se requieren en todos los cursos. En especial, faltan las actividades de pensamiento crítico, tan esenciales en disciplinas como las humanidades, las ciencias sociales y los negocios. Intentamos convencer a algunos profesores de humanidades, de que las preguntas de opción múltiple, no eran tan mala estrategia. Pero no funcionó bien. Tuvimos que idear otra solución, y llegamos a la evaluación por pares. De acuerdo a estudios previos, como este de Saddler y Good, la evaluación por pares es una estrategia efectiva para conseguir calificaciones reproducibles. Solo se ha usado en clases pequeñas, pero se demostró, por ejemplo, que las calificaciones asignadas por alumnos, en el eje Y, están muy bien correlacionadas con la calificación asignada por el maestro, en el eje X. Aún más sorprendente es que las calificaciones autoasignadas, cuando los mismos estudiantes calificaron su trabajo, —en tanto los incentivos sean apropiados y no puedan asignarse una calificación perfecta— tuvieran aún mejor correlación con la calificación asignada por el maestro. Así que ésta es una estrategia efectiva para calificar a gran escala y también para enriquecer el aprendizaje, pues los estudiantes aprenden de la experiencia. Contamos con el mayor sistema de evaluación por pares jamás concebido, decenas de miles de estudiantes están calificando el trabajo de sus compañeros y exitosamente, hay que decirlo. Pero no se trata de tenerlos aislados en un cuarto resolviendo problemas. En cada curso se formó una comunidad de estudiantes. Son comunidades globales que comparten un esfuerzo intelectual. Aquí ven un mapa generado por los estudiantes del curso Sociología 101, de Princeton, donde marcaron su localización en un planisferio. Pueden apreciar el alcance global de la iniciativa. Los estudiantes colaboraron entre ellos de varias formas. Primero, había un foro de preguntas y respuestas, donde algunos estudiantes planteaban sus dudas y otros las respondían. Lo maravilloso es que, debido a la gran cantidad de alumnos, si alguno hacía una pregunta a las 3 de la madrugada, en alguna parte del mundo alguien estaba despierto y trabajando en el mismo problema. Por lo que en muchos de nuestros cursos el tiempo de respuesta promedio en el foro, era de 22 minutos. Es un nivel de servicio que nunca he ofrecido a mis alumnos en Stanford. (Risas) Y pueden ver por sus testimonios, que estos estudiantes creen que debido a esta gran comunidad en línea, pudieron interactuar unos con otros en varias formas más profundas que las que habían tenido en un aula. Además, los estudiantes se organizaron sin nuestra intervención en pequeños grupos de estudio. Algunos se establecieron físicamente a partir de limitaciones geográficas, y se reunían cada semana a trabajar en los problemas. Éste es el grupo de San Francisco, pero los había en todo el mundo. Otros grupos eran virtuales, centrados alrededor de un idioma u otro elemento cultural. Y abajo, a la izquierda, pueden ver el grupo multicultural, cuyos miembros deseaban explícitamente interactuar con personas de otras culturas. Hay enormes oportunidades en este tipo de contexto. Primero, tiene el potencial de darnos una mirada sin precedente en el entendimiento del aprendizaje, porque podemos recopilar información única. Se pueden recopilar todos los clics, tareas y entradas en el foro, de decenas de miles de estudiantes. Así, el estudio del aprendizaje puede pasar de estar fundamentado en hipótesis a estar fundamentado en datos, un cambio que, por ejemplo, revolucionó la biología. Los datos pueden ayudar a responder preguntas fundamentales, como qué estrategias de aprendizaje son efectivas y cuáles no.
And in the context of particular courses, you can ask questions like, what are some of the misconceptions that are more common and how do we help students fix them? So here's an example of that, also from Andrew's Machine Learning class. This is a distribution of wrong answers to one of Andrew's assignments. The answers happen to be pairs of numbers, so you can draw them on this two-dimensional plot. Each of the little crosses that you see is a different wrong answer. The big cross at the top left is where 2,000 students gave the exact same wrong answer. Now, if two students in a class of 100 give the same wrong answer, you would never notice. But when 2,000 students give the same wrong answer, it's kind of hard to miss. So Andrew and his students went in, looked at some of those assignments, understood the root cause of the misconception, and then they produced a targeted error message that would be provided to every student whose answer fell into that bucket, which means that students who made that same mistake would now get personalized feedback telling them how to fix their misconception much more effectively. So this personalization is something that one can then build by having the virtue of large numbers. Personalization is perhaps one of the biggest opportunities here as well, because it provides us with the potential of solving a 30-year-old problem. Educational researcher Benjamin Bloom, in 1984, posed what's called the 2 sigma problem, which he observed by studying three populations. The first is the population that studied in a lecture-based classroom. The second is a population of students that studied using a standard lecture-based classroom, but with a mastery-based approach, so the students couldn't move on to the next topic before demonstrating mastery of the previous one. And finally, there was a population of students that were taught in a one-on-one instruction using a tutor. The mastery-based population was a full standard deviation, or sigma, in achievement scores better than the standard lecture-based class, and the individual tutoring gives you 2 sigma improvement in performance. To understand what that means, let's look at the lecture-based classroom, and let's pick the median performance as a threshold. So in a lecture-based class, half the students are above that level and half are below. In the individual tutoring instruction, 98 percent of the students are going to be above that threshold. Imagine if we could teach so that 98 percent of our students would be above average. Hence, the 2 sigma problem. Because we cannot afford, as a society, to provide every student with an individual human tutor. But maybe we can afford to provide each student with a computer or a smartphone. So the question is, how can we use technology to push from the left side of the graph, from the blue curve, to the right side with the green curve? Mastery is easy to achieve using a computer, because a computer doesn't get tired of showing you the same video five times. And it doesn't even get tired of grading the same work multiple times, we've seen that in many of the examples that I've shown you. And even personalization is something that we're starting to see the beginnings of, whether it's via the personalized trajectory through the curriculum or some of the personalized feedback that we've shown you. So the goal here is to try and push, and see how far we can get towards the green curve. So, if this is so great, are universities now obsolete? Well, Mark Twain certainly thought so. He said that, "College is a place where a professor's lecture notes go straight to the students' lecture notes, without passing through the brains of either." (Laughter) I beg to differ with Mark Twain, though. I think what he was complaining about is not universities but rather the lecture-based format that so many universities spend so much time on. So let's go back even further, to Plutarch, who said that, "The mind is not a vessel that needs filling, but wood that needs igniting." And maybe we should spend less time at universities filling our students' minds with content by lecturing at them, and more time igniting their creativity, their imagination and their problem-solving skills by actually talking with them. So how do we do that? We do that by doing active learning in the classroom. So there's been many studies, including this one, that show that if you use active learning, interacting with your students in the classroom, performance improves on every single metric -- on attendance, on engagement and on learning as measured by a standardized test. You can see, for example, that the achievement score almost doubles in this particular experiment. So maybe this is how we should spend our time at universities. So to summarize, if we could offer a top quality education to everyone around the world for free, what would that do? Three things. First it would establish education as a fundamental human right, where anyone around the world with the ability and the motivation could get the skills that they need to make a better life for themselves, their families and their communities. Second, it would enable lifelong learning. It's a shame that for so many people, learning stops when we finish high school or when we finish college. By having this amazing content be available, we would be able to learn something new every time we wanted, whether it's just to expand our minds or it's to change our lives. And finally, this would enable a wave of innovation, because amazing talent can be found anywhere. Maybe the next Albert Einstein or the next Steve Jobs is living somewhere in a remote village in Africa. And if we could offer that person an education, they would be able to come up with the next big idea and make the world a better place for all of us. Thank you very much. (Applause)
Y para cada curso particular se pueden preguntar cosas como, cuáles son las equivocaciones más comunes y cómo ayudar a los estudiantes a corregirlas. Aquí hay un ejemplo, también de la clase de Aprendizaje automático, es la distribución de respuestas erróneas de una de las tareas. Las respuestas vinieron a ser pares de números, por lo que se pudieron graficar en dos ejes. Cada pequeña cruz es una respuesta errada diferente. La grande de arriba es de 2000 estudiantes que cometieron exactamente el mismo error. Ahora, si dos estudiantes en una clase de 100 cometen el mismo error, puedes no percibirlo. Pero cuando se trata de 2000 estudiantes, es imposible ignorarlo. Andrew y sus estudiantes revisaron algunas de las tareas para entender la causa de la equivocación y elaboraron una explicación específica que enviaron a quienes daban esa respuesta equivocada, y así los estudiantes que cometían ese error recibían retroalimentación personalizada indicándoles de manera efectiva cómo corregirlo. Esta personalización es posible gracias a la gran cantidad de información recopilada. La personalización representa una de las mayores oportunidades aquí, porque nos da la posibilidad de resolver un problema de 30 años. En 1984, el investigador educacional, Benjamin Bloom planteó el llamado problema de las dos sigmas, que observó al estudiar tres grupos de estudiantes. El primero estudiaba en un aula tradicional, a base de conferencias. El segundo también estudiaba a base de conferencias, pero con un enfoque dirigido a objetivos, de tal forma que los estudiantes no avanzaban sin antes dominar el tema anterior. Y en el último grupo, un tutor daba instrucción individual a los estudiantes. El grupo basado en aprendizaje dirigido a objetivos obtuvo una desviación estándar o una sigma, por encima del rendimiento del grupo corriente con clases basadas en conferencias. Y la instrucción individual produjo una mejora de dos sigmas en el rendimiento. Para entender qué significa, veamos la clase basada en conferencias y tomemos el valor medio como umbral. Así, en la clase basada en conferencias, la mitad está por encima de ese nivel y la otra mitad por debajo. En el caso de la instrucción individual, el 98 % estará por encima de ese nivel. Imaginen lograr que el 98 % de los estudiantes superara ese promedio. De aquí el problema de las dos sigmas, dado que no podemos costear, como sociedad, el darle a cada estudiante un tutor humano individual. Pero quizá podamos darles una computadora o un teléfono inteligente. La pregunta es, ¿cómo usar la tecnología para ir de la zona izquierda, de la curva azul, a la zona derecha de la curva verde? Es fácil dominar un tema usando una computadora, porque esta no se cansa de repetir el mismo video cinco veces, ni siquiera de calificar una actividad muchas veces, como les he mostrado en muchos de los ejemplos. Incluso estamos viendo los inicios de la instrucción personalizada, bien sea a través del currículo o de la retroalimentación personalizada. La meta aquí es probar, impulsar y ver cuánto nos acercamos a la curva verde. Así que, si esto es tan bueno, ¿son obsoletas las universidades? Bueno, así lo creía Mark Twain, quien dijo: "La universidad es el lugar donde los apuntes del profesor van directo a los del estudiante, sin pasar por el cerebro de ninguno de ellos". (Risas) Sin embargo, me permito disentir de Mark Twain. Creo que lo que criticaba no eran las universidades, sino las clases basadas en conferencias a las que estas dedican gran parte del tiempo. Así que retrocedamos, hasta Plutarco, quien dijo: " La mente no es un vaso por llenar, sino una lámpara por encender". Quizá debamos dedicar menos tiempo a llenar de conferencias las mentes de los estudiantes y dedicar más tiempo a encender su creatividad, su imaginación y sus habilidades de resolución de problemas, a partir de la interacción genuina con ellos. ¿Cómo lograrlo? Lo hacemos adoptando el aprendizaje activo. Numerosos estudios, incluyendo éste, demuestran que si se emplea el aprendizaje activo, interactuando con los estudiantes en el aula, mejoran todos los indicadores de rendimiento: asistencia, compromiso y aprendizaje medidos en exámenes estandarizados. Pueden ver que, por ejemplo, el nivel de logro mejora hasta el doble en este experimento. Quizá así debamos usar el tiempo en las universidades. En resumen, si pudiéramos ofrecer educación de calidad a todos en el mundo, gratuitamente, ¿Qué supondría esto? Tres cosas. Primero, la educación se establecería como un derecho fundamental. Cualquier persona en el mundo con la capacidad y la motivación, podría desarrollar las habilidades que necesitara para mejorar autónomamente su calidad de vida, la de su familia y su comunidad. Segundo, permitiría el aprendizaje continuo. Es una lástima que para muchos el aprendizaje termine al completar la escuela secundaria o la universidad. Al tener disponible esta asombrosa colección de cursos, es posible aprender algo nuevo cuando se desee, ya sea para expandir nuestras mentes o para cambiar nuestras vidas. Por último, impulsaría una ola de innovación, porque en todas partes hay talento asombroso. Quizá el próximo Albert Einstein o el próximo Steve Jobs viva en una villa remota en África. Y si pudiéramos ofrecerle una educación, podría ser capaz de producir la nueva gran idea y hacer del mundo un lugar mejor para todos nosotros. Muchísimas gracias. (Aplausos)